Register of the Benton Clark Decker Papers, 1914-1921
Hoover Institution Archives
Benton Clark Decker Papers
1914-1921
74078
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 envelope (0.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, lectures, notes, and photographs, relating to activities of the U.S.S. Tennessee, Spanish neutrality, and refugees in the Middle East, during World War I.
Decker, Benton Clark, 1867-1933
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Biographical/Historical note
Rear admiral, United States Navy; captain, U.S.S. Tennessee; naval attaché to Spain.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, lectures, notes, and photographs, relating to activities of the U.S.S. Tennessee, Spanish neutrality, and refugees in the Middle East, during World War I.
Tennessee (Ship); United States. Navy--Officers; International relief.; Middle East.; Spain--Military relations--United States.; Spain.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Military relations--Spain.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations.; World War, 1914-1918--Spain.; World War, 1914-1918.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1916, 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - American Embassy, Constantinople, 1921 August 15
  - Comité d'Assistance aux Refugiés de Palestine, 1915 February 26
  - Daniels, Josephus (Secretary of the Navy), 1915-1916
  - Hayden, Mr., 1916 October 11
  - Lansing, Robert, 1915 November 18
  - Morgenthau, Henry, 1921 December 17
  - Riordan, D. M., 1914 September 9
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1915-1916
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1921
  - Award of Navy medals, 1920 January
  - The Battle of Jutland, Comments on, by B. C. Decker
  - Calling cards, invitations, notes, from various individuals
  - "The Enviable Record of the Cruiser 'Tennessee' Soon to Be Named the 'Memphis'"
  - "Handling Men," by Lieutenant R. A. Theobald, United States Navy, with Discussion by Captain B. C. Decker, United States Navy
  - Jewish refugees in Egypt, 1915
  - Lecture by Benton C. Decker, Captain, United States Navy
  - "Naval Men and Their Management," by Lieutenant V. N. Bieg, United States Navy
  - Spain - B. C. Decker's service as US Naval Attaché, Madrid, Spain
  - "Spain's Attitude Towards the War," by Captain B. C. Decker, United States Navy, 1918 June 7
  - Statement of Rear Admiral B. C. Decker, United States Navy, made for the purpose of securing the position of Rear Admiral in the permanent service
  - Tributes to B. C. Decker
  - U.S.S. Tennessee
  - "What Shall Be the Size of the Navy?"
  - Miscellaneous
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Photo file)
  Scope and Contents note
  80 prints depicting scenes on the U.S.S "Tennessee" and places visited by Captain B.C. Decker, primarily Egypt and Spain.